# Ana Todović

Address: Dositejeva 2, Beograd

Phone: +38166062363

E-mail: <u>ana.todovic@gmail.com</u>



#### SUMMARY

For more than 5 years I've been programming and working on large scale software development projects. I have experience in various technologies in developing frontend and backend, and now I have the most interest in Node.js and React. JavaScript is very exciting for me because it's "easy to learn, but hard to master". It's very simple but it has countless small catches that can make programmers life heaven and hell at the same time.

I enjoy working in a team and being a mentor, but also love developing software and solving problems individually. I've been working by Scrum for years most of the time following continuous delivery approach. I'm familiar with version control, Jenkins, Ansible deployment and various other tools and approaches that make large, fast-changing software projects possible to manage.

#### COMPUTER SKILLS

- Proficient in JavaScript, Node.js, React, Redux, React Router, Babel, Webpack, Selenium, Jest, HTML, CSS
- Familiar with Ansible, Docker, GitHub, TortoiseSVN and Jenkins CI server, Python, C, C++ etc.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Senior Software Developer**

Feb 2015 – present

Comtrade software

- Working on date protection automated backup and recovery software for single-server to enterprise environments. It provides crossplatform, online backup of data for Microsoft Windows, Unix, and Linux operating systems. My responsibility was mainly maintenance of core component written in C programming language.
- Developing remote connectivity software solution which enables connections to devices on customer networks for remote service delivery, support automation, real time monitoring and feedback. My work was mainly oriented to implementing completely new UI design written in React and Grommet.
- Developing UI for various parts of support portal implementing UI solutions in React, also using Ansible, Grafana, Prometheus and other tools and technics for building and maintaining large environment.

## **Software Developer**

Jul 2013 - Jan 2015

PS Tech, Belgrade

Development of an application that provides chat, video, voice and conference calls between various devices and a plugin to make ensure this application works for virtualized environment on embedded Linux and Windows operating systems. Working on this project included developing communication between client machine and HVD, preparing custom made embedded releases for specific customers, maintenance of virtual channel etc. Code was mostly written in C++.

### **EDUCATION**

## Faculty of Mathematics, University of Belgrade

- **Bachelor of Computer Science**
- Master of Science in Astroinformatics

2005 - 2012